{"tossups": [{"question": "A character in this story gives his wife a book of poems entirely in German. Dr. Sivetski calls it a \u201cperfect crime\u201d that the Army released that man from the hospital. A little girl in this story repeatedly asks her mother a question that sounds like another character\u2019s name. In this story, a character plays the piano and causes conflict with another character by sharing his piano bench. One character in this work kisses a girl\u2019s (*) feet and explains how certain animals get a disease named after the food they eat. That character plays with Sybil Carpenter and is the source of Muriel\u2019s mother\u2019s anxiety about a beach vacation. Seymour Glass abruptly kills himself at the end of, for 10 points, what short story by J.D. Salinger?", "answer": "\u201cA Perfect Day for Bananafish\u201d", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cA Perfect Day for Bananafish\u201d</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cA Perfect Day for Bananafish\u201d", "\u201cA Perfect Day for Bananafish\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This is the profession of Luba Luft, who is killed in an elevator in Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep? In another novel, Ray Kennedy dreams of marrying a 12 year old girl who falls in love with this profession when she travels to Chicago. That girl trains for this profession with Madison Bowers after leaving Moonstone, Colorado. Another character with this profession threatens suicide as a man tries to drown \u201cThe Persian\u201d and her love interest. That character with this profession buries her kidnapper with a (*) gold ring he had given her as a present. The title character of that work kidnaps a woman of this profession after she replaces Carlotta and calls himself the \u201cAngel of Music\u201d while training her. Thea Kronborg and Christine Daa\u00e9 have, for 10 points, what musical profession haunted by a title \u201cphantom\u201d in a Gaston Leroux novel?", "answer": "opera singer [accept equivalents; prompt on singer, performer, or equivalent; do not accept any specific vocal parts except soprano]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "opera <b><u>singer</u></b> [accept equivalents; prompt on <u>singer, performer,</u> or <u>equivalent</u>; do not accept \"any specific vocal parts except soprano\"]", "acceptable": ["opera singer", "singer"], "promptable": ["singer, performer,", "equivalent"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel is forced to wear a blue silk dress and mascara so that guards can abuse him. The protagonist of this novel writes a story about a man who stabs his wife to make himself weep, because his tears turn into pearls. A man fires two characters in this novel after his son hides birthday money and a gold watch under a pillow. One character in this novel beats another with brass knuckles before getting shot in the eye with a slingshot. Rahim (*) Khan convinces the protagonist of this novel to save Sohrab, whom the protagonist adopts and takes to San Francisco. In this novel, Assef rapes a Hazara servant in an alley while his friend watches. This novel is titled after the action Hassan performs for Amir during contests in Kabul. For 10 points, name this first novel by Khaled Hosseini.", "answer": "The Kite Runner", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Kite Runner</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Kite Runner", "Kite Runner"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author coined the term for an art and poetry movement in the short-lived magazine BLAST. This author wrote in that essay, \u201cEvery concept, every motion presents itself to the vivid consciousness in some primary form.\u201d In one poem by this author, he describes \"pallid\" and \"half-awakened\" gods that have been reduced to nothing; that poem is titled \"The Return.\" In another poem, this writer describes a conversation with Mr. Nixon who tells the speaker to (*) \"give up verse, my boy,\" repeating the idea that poetry is a \"dead art.\" In another of this man's poems, he likens the image of \"faces in the crowd\" to flower petals. For 10 points, name this modernist poet who wrote poems such as \"Hugh Selwyn Mauberley\" and \"In the Station of the Metro.\"", "answer": "Ezra Pound", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Ezra <b><u>Pound</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ezra Pound", "Pound"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Two characters in this poem are \u201clike two pigeons in one nest / Folded in each other\u2019s wings.\u201d In this poem, Jeanie \u201cpined and pined away,\u201d and after her death, \u201cno grass will grow / Where she lies low.\u201d One character in this poem tries to plant a \u201ckernel-stone\u201d watered with her tears but it \u201cnever saw the sun.\u201d The protagonist of this poem tells her sister to \u201chug me, kiss me, (*) suck my juices.\u201d When a character in this poem does not have any method to pay for fruit, the title people say to \u201cbuy from us with a golden curl.\u201d The title people of this poem shout \u201ccome buy our orchard fruits, / Come buy, come buy.\u201d For 10 points, name this poem in which Laura and Lizzie resist the calls of the title creatures, written by Christina Rossetti.", "answer": "\u201cGoblin Market\u201d", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cGoblin Market\u201d</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cGoblin Market\u201d", "\u201cGoblin Market\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a play by this author, it is revealed that the Dead Man was once a slave who was sold for a flask of rum. That play concludes with the central group exiting as a forest is smoked out. A character created by this author describes a stamp as \u201ca tax on / The habit of talking with paper,\u201d and was told by a modernist that women are less intelligent than men due to their smaller brains. In a play by this author, a medical student tells a woman that her people (*) \u201chave no respect for what [they] cannot understand.\u201d Lakunle is unable to pay a bride price in a play by this author, and another begins with the protagonist chanting about the Not-I bird. Olunde commits ritual suicide in place of his father Elesin in that play due to the intervention of Simon Pilkings. For 10 points, name this Nigerian playwright of The Lion and the Jewel and Death and the King\u2019s Horseman.", "answer": "Wole Soyinka (the first two clues are from A Dance of the Forests)", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Wole <b><u>Soyinka</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Wole Soyinka", "Soyinka"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "the first two clues are from A Dance of the Forests"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel faints after reading a letter that states, \u201cWe will never, ever see each other again.\u201d A cellist leaves for Montenegro midway through a performance in this novel because he is told someone there is dying. A lawyer commits suicide by jumping off a train and the dressmaker Amalia attempts to poison herself in this novel. This novel\u2019s protagonist dies of a heart attack while riding a tram and is abducted by the cocaine addict Liberius, a commander of the (*) Forest Brotherhood. The protagonist\u2019s love interest in this novel is married to a man nicknamed \u201cThe Shooter.\u201d That man, Strelnikov, commits suicide, after which the protagonist finds his body. A woman shoots Kornakov in this novel, part of which takes place during the Russian Revolution. For 10 points, name this novel about the title lover of Lara by Boris Pasternak.", "answer": "Doctor Zhivago", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Doctor Zhivago</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Doctor Zhivago", "Doctor Zhivago"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this novel walks up and down the lawn steps, looking down as if he \u201choped to find some precious jewel he dropped there.\u201d The protagonist of this novel is asked to give the \u201csex talk\u201d to Mr. Cardinal, but fails because he does not know how to talk about sex. The protagonist of this novel defends another character by stating that Herr Ribbentrop was not always a \u201ctrickster\u201d and that many Englishmen stayed with members of the (*) Nazi regime. The narrator of this novel desires to perfect the art of \u201cbantering\u201d so he can get along with his new employer, Mr. Farraday. That narrator also travels to the home of Miss Kenton, hoping to bring her back to Darlington Hall. For 10 points, name this Kazuo Ishiguro novel narrated by the butler Stevens.", "answer": "The Remains of the Day", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Remains of the Day</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Remains of the Day", "Remains of the Day"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of this author\u2019s characters notes that man has watched the title animals \u201cfor centuries prior to this time.\u201d This author also created Bernard Litko, who comforts his friend Danny Shapiro with insulting talk of \u201cbroads\u201d after Danny and his girlfriend Deborah Solomon break up. In another of this author\u2019s works, George refuses to participate in Dave\u2019s scheme to rob the central establishment. This author of The Duck Variations and (*) Sexual Perversity in Chicago wrote about Karen\u2019s seduction of the Hollywood executive Bobby Gould in another work. This author of Speed-the-Plow featured Shelley \u201cThe Machine\u201d Levine as one of several salesmen who work under the manager John Williamson. For 10 points, name this famously profane playwright, who wrote about Ricky Roma\u2019s attempts to sell real estate in Glengarry Glen Ross.", "answer": "David Mamet", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "David <b><u>Mamet</u></b>", "acceptable": ["David Mamet", "Mamet"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem by this author describes \u201cspellbound horses\u201d and a \u201cmoon that is always rising.\u201d The author describes himself as \u201chuntsman and herdsman\u201d and \u201cfamous among the barns\u201d in that poem. Another poem by this author mentions the \u201cwindings of the sea\u201d and \u201cunicorn evils.\u201d People are \u201cmad\u201d and \u201cdead as nails\u201d in that poem, which claims that their \u201cbones are picked clean\u201d and their \u201cclean bones gone.\u201d This author wrote about the \u201cfrail deeds\u201d of \u201cgood men\u201d in one poem, and \u201cTime\u201d holds him (*) \u201cgreen and dying\u201d in another poem in which he was \u201cyoung and easy under the apple boughs.\u201d This author wrote about \u201cgrave men, who see with blinding sight\u201d in a poem which urges the listener to \u201crage, rage against the dying of the light.\u201d For 10 points, name this Welsh poet who wrote \u201cFern Hill\u201d and \u201cDo not go gentle into that good night.\u201d", "answer": "Dylan (Marlais) Thomas", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Dylan <b><u>Thomas</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Dylan Thomas", "Thomas"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Marlais"}, {"question": "After admiring the architecture of one building, a character in this novel imagines that structure with his desired tomb inscription, \u201cthose who have secretly understood my heart.\u201d A character in this novel distinguishes the terms \u201cmuddle\u201d and \u201cmystery\u201d after carriages arrive late to an angry group of women. At the end of this novel, a group of men fall into a rowboat accident, coinciding with the climax of a religious festival nearby. (*) Major Callendar frequently debates with a woman in this novel who uses a pair of broken glasses as evidence against one character. Mrs. Moore\u2019s son Ronny Heaslop falls in love but does not marry a character who falsely accuses Dr. Aziz of rape near the Malabar Caves. For 10 points, name this novel featuring Adela Quested, penned by E.M Forster.", "answer": "A Passage To India", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "A <b><u>Passage To India</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Passage To India", "Passage To India"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character concludes that the response of a schoolboy was lying at the bottom of \u201cspurious profundity\u201d attributed to Machiavelli and Campanella. In another work, this protagonist tries to figure out the origin of a gruff voice which vaguely utters the words \u201csacre\u201d and \u201cdiable,\u201d as well another, more inscrutable shrill voice. At the end of that story, this character mentions that a local Prefect named G- was \u201ctoo cunning to be profound.\u201d This character describes the marble-guessing game \u201ceven and odd\u201d and wears thick green spectacles as a disguise to obtain a (*) document found in a card rack from Minister D. In another appearance, this character deduces that an orangutan killed Madame L'Espanaye and her daughter near a Paris quarter. For 10 points, name this detective featured in a trio of short stories by Edgar Allen Poe.", "answer": "C. Auguste Dupin [accept either underlined part]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>C. Auguste Dupin</u></b> [accept <b><u>either underlined part</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["C. Auguste Dupin", "C. Auguste Dupin", "either underlined part"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem by this author ends by saying those who live alone will \u201calong the city\u2019s avenues / fitfully wander when the wild leaves loosen.\u201d The speaker of a poem by this author calls the central figures \u201cEarly successes, Creation\u2019s favorite ones.\u201d This author found the inspiration for one poem from instruction by Auguste Rodin; that poem describes the title (*) creature\u2019s view of \u201ca curtain of pupils.\u201d Another poem by this author describes the title figure as \u201csuffused with brilliance from inside\u201d and ends with the declaration \u201cYou must change your life.\u201d This author began his most famous collection with the line \u201cWho, if I cried out, would hear me among the Angelic orders?\u201d For 10 points, what German poet wrote \u201cThe Panther,\" \u201cThe Archaic Torso of Apollo,\" and the Duino Elegies?", "answer": "Rainer Maria Rilke", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Rainer Maria <b><u>Rilke</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Rainer Maria Rilke", "Rilke"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Members of this family are classified as \u201cthe ones who live by the dump\u201d when another character describes the four kinds of people. One member of this family is asked \u201cDo you have any friends?\u201d and is offended when a man calls her \u201cma\u2019am.\" Another member of this family is permitted to hunt out of season and is named after a (*) Confederate general. One member of this family uses a broken chiffarobe as an excuse to have a man enter her home and starts crying when shown the difference in the length of that man\u2019s arms at a rape trial. One member of this family is deemed to have fallen on his knife despite having actually been killed by Boo Radley. For 10 points, name this racist white family with members Mayella and Bob, the antagonists of To Kill a Mockingbird.", "answer": "the Ewell family", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "the <b><u>Ewell family</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the Ewell family", "Ewell family"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The son of a character created by this author attempts to avoid conscription by hitchhiking to Namibia. A character created by this author is criticized by a childhood friend at a political event for never learning the friend\u2019s real name; that character\u2019s father Lionel earlier died in prison. In a novel by this author, the protagonist accuses her son Victor of stealing a gun, and later becomes paranoid about her servant taking her (*) car keys. The title character of a novel by this author decides to exile herself in France after encouragement from her lover Bernard. A dead body is swept back to the surface by a flood in a novel by this author, causing Mehring to leave his farm in the hands of Jacobus, and another novel by this author ends with Maureen Smales running to a helicopter. For 10 points, what South African author wrote The Conservationist, Burger\u2019s Daughter, and July\u2019s People?", "answer": "Nadine Gordimer", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Nadine <b><u>Gordimer</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nadine Gordimer", "Gordimer"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of one play by this author notes that \u201cthey\u2019re all gone now, and there isn\u2019t anything more the [title location] can do to me\u201d before asking for \u201cHoly Water.\u201d Another play by this author sparked protest after using the word \u201cshift,\u201d referring to women\u2019s undergarments. Bartley ignores his mother\u2019s request to stay and plans to go to Connemara, resulting in his death in a play by this author. In that play, (*) Maurya laments the death of five sons and a husband who all died at the title location. In one of his plays, Christy Mahon becomes a local hero after claiming to have killed his father with a spade, contributing to real-life riots at the Abbey Theater. For 10 points, name this Irish playwright of Riders to the Sea and Playboy of the Western World.", "answer": "John Millington Synge", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "John Millington <b><u>Synge</u></b>", "acceptable": ["John Millington Synge", "Synge"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A mother in this novel returns home to cook soup containing a piece of flesh cut off from her own arm. The Second Wife blackmails another character in this novel by threatening to commit suicide. The protagonist of this novel is told a story by her mother about her running away from Kweilin with three fancy dresses. Lindo dons an \u201cAmerican face\u201d when taken to a beauty parlor by her daughter in a section of this novel titled (*) \u201cQueen Mother of the Western Skies.\u201d A trip to the beach results in Bing drowning in this novel, which saddens his older sister Rose Hsu Jordan. Waverly becomes a national chess champion at the age of nine in this novel. This novel opens with Jing Mei-Woo replacing her mother Suyuan at the head of the title group\u2019s mahjong table. For 10 points, name this novel about the title group of Chinese-American women, written by Amy Tan.", "answer": "The Joy Luck Club", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Joy Luck Club</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Joy Luck Club", "Joy Luck Club"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in one play by this author threatens to disrupt the coronation of Queen Victoria if the sheriff cannot prevent an elopement. The protagonist of a play by this author sings \u201cThe Song of Great Capitulation,\u201d which convinces a soldier to withdraw his complaints. This playwright described acting in a way that prevented the audience from identifying with the characters in the play to achieve a (*) \u201cdistancing effect.\u201d He\u2019s not John Gay, but \u201cMack the Knife\u201d marries Polly Peachum in a play by this author. Anna Fierling travels in a wagon to sell supplies to soldiers in the Thirty Years\u2019 War with her children Kattrin, Eilif, and Swiss Cheese in another of this author\u2019s plays. For 10 points, name this playwright of The Threepenny Opera and Mother Courage and Her Children.", "answer": "Bertolt Brecht", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Bertolt <b><u>Brecht</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Bertolt Brecht", "Brecht"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a narrative written in this language, a man whose name means \u201cSon of Sycamore\u201d cries, \"May the King have mercy on me...may I be conducted to the city of eternity,\" pleading to be buried in his home country despite having deserted his duties as an official. Another work written in this language of the Story of Sinuhe describes how individuals who pass through caves, mazes, and gates guarded by creatures like \"He who lives on snakes\" and \"He who dances in blood\" can enjoy the lush (*) Field of Reeds, or Aaru. In that text, Spell 125 explains the rules for weighing a deceased person's heart against the goddess Maat, symbolized by an ostrich feather. If a person failed that test described in this language, his mummified heart would be eaten. For 10 points, in what language did scribes produce the Book of the Dead and the top section of the Rosetta Stone?", "answer": "Ancient Egyptian [also accept hieroglyphics or hieratic]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ancient Egyptian</u></b> [also accept hieroglyphics or hieratic]", "acceptable": ["Ancient Egyptian", "Ancient Egyptian"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A woman uses a twig to draw a line in the sand that never disappears in one novel by this author. In another novel by this author set in 1551, Solomon is given to Archduke Maximilian as a present. Characters in a novel by this author describe a painting that combines multiple works by different artists, such as Francisco de Goya and Leonardo da Vinci. A man with a radio and a woman who eats chickens and rabbits are characters in that novel, in which that woman is found dead holding a set of (*) keys. A dog licks a woman\u2019s face in that novel by this author, leading it to be called the \u201cdog of tears.\" Other characters in that novel include a girl with dark glasses and an old man with an eye patch. For 10 points, name this Portuguese author of The Stone Raft, The Elephant\u2019s Journey, and Blindness.", "answer": "Jos\u00e9 de Sousa Saramago", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Jos\u00e9 de Sousa <b><u>Saramago</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Jos\u00e9 de Sousa Saramago", "Saramago"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}